Xenia Dennen papers, Inclusive: 1931-2016, undated, Bulk: 1986-1998
Baylor University, The Keston Center for Religion, Politics, and Society
Xenia Dennen papers
Inclusive: 1931-2016, undated, Bulk: 1986-1998
Baylor University, The Keston Center for Religion, Politics, and Society http://www.baylor.edu/kestoncenter/
2
Xenia Dennen, 1944-present
14 document boxes
The Xenia Dennen Papers contain materials produced or collected by Xenia Dennen, Chair of the Council of Management of the Keston Institute in Oxford, United Kingdom.
Administrative Information
Physical Description
General condition: Excellent.
Biography/Profile
Xenia Violet Howard-Johnston Dennen was born in Liverpool on March 11, 1944, to Rear-Admiral Clarence Dinsmore Howard-Johnston and Lady Alexandra Henrietta Louisa Haig.
Dennen received a degree in Russian and French from Oxford University in 1966. Her interest in Russia stemmed from her paternal grandmother whose family, the Bairds, lived in Russia from the late 18th century until 1882. Soon after graduation, Michael Bourdeaux employed her as his assistant, researching the religious situation in the Soviet Union. To acquire greater understanding of the country, she earned a graduate degree in Russian politics from the London School of Economics and Political Science while working as a research assistant for Professor Leonard Schapiro.
In 1969, Dennen helped found The Centre for the Study of Religion and Communism (later to be called Keston College and eventually Keston Institute) and became a member of its Council of Management. She began producing Keston’s academic journal Religion in Communist Lands (changed to Religion, State and Society after the fall of communism) in 1973 and continued as editor until 1981.
During the 1990s, Dennen served as Keston’s Moscow representative, travelling to Russia four to six times a year and building a network of contacts. There, she met Sergei Filatov and introduced his idea of producing an encyclopedia about the contemporary position of all religions in Russia to Michael Bourdeaux. The Keston Institute formed an encyclopedia team of which Dennen became a member. Since 1999, she has been actively involved in the team’s field work, visiting various regions in Russia four to five times a year, and in producing the multi-volume Encyclopaedia of Religious Life in Russia Today.
Dennen has chaired the Keston Institute Council of Management since 2002 and serves on the Court of the Mercers’ Company in London. She is married to the Venerable Lyle Dennen, a priest in the Church of England. They have two grown sons.
Scope and Content
The Xenia Dennen Papers cover the period from 1931 to 2016 with the bulk from 1986 to 1998 and focus on issues of religion, church-state relations, state legislation on religion, and religious dissidents mainly in the former Soviet Union and Russia.
Series I is the largest in the collection. Subject Files consist of materials divided by topics. Topics pertaining to the former Soviet Union and Russia include the Russian Orthodox Church Abroad; Missionaries; Theological and religious education; Bogorodichnyi Tsentr (Center of the Mother of God); Russian law on religion; Islam; Buddhism; Totalitarian sects; Abuse of psychiatry, dissidents Fr. Gleb Yakunin and Zoya Krakhmalnikova, and a politician Galina Starovoitova. Other topics include the 1968 Soviet invasion of Czechoslovakia, the 1986 British Council of Churches visit to the Soviet Union, and the 1988 Keston Conference on Christianity in Slavic lands.
The two remaining series are smaller. Series II, Collected Works, consists of materials published by others. Series III, Literary Productions, contains Dennen’s own written works, primarily diaries of Keston Encyclopedia project field trips.
Arrangement
Xenia Dennen Papers arrived in large pocket folders with titles. This original filing system has been preserved.
Currently the collection is organized into three series: I. Subject Files, II. Collected Materials, and III. Literary Productions.
Access Restrictions
All requests for copying of materials must be submitted to the Keston Center for Religion, Politics, and Society in writing. Please use the Request Form for Copying Materials sheet. Unpublished materials authored or otherwise produced by the creator (s) of this collection are in the public domain. There are no restrictions on use. Copyright status for other collection materials is unknown. Transmission or reproduction of materials protected by U.S. Copyright Law (Title 17, U.S.C.) beyond that allowed by fair use requires the written permission of the copyright owners. Works not in the public domain cannot be commercially exploited without permission of the copyright owners. Responsibility for any use rests exclusively with the user.
Acquisition Information
Accession No. 2.
Index Terms
Subjects (Persons)
Dennen, Xenia -- Archives.; Krakhmal'nikova, Zoia, 1929-2008.; Riga, Sandr, 1939-
Subjects (Organizations)
Bogorodichnyi tsentr (Firm: Moscow, Russia); Keston Institute.
Places
Czechoslovakia -- History -- Intervention, 1968.; Russia (Federation) -- Politics and government -- 1991-
Subjects
Freedom of religion -- Russia (Federation); Human rights -- Russia (Federation); Persecution -- Russia (Federation); Religion and state -- Russia (Federation)
Genres
Clippings (Books, newspapers, etc.); Correspondence.; Diaries.; Photographs.
- Subject Files, 1969-2009, undated; 1
  Administrative Information
  Biography/Profile
  The largest series in the collection consists of newspaper clippings, research papers, reports, manuscripts, handwritten notes, correspondence, and publications collected for Dennen’s personal research or produced as a result of her affiliation with the Keston Institute, the Keston Moscow Office, or the Keston Council of Management.
  - The Russian Orthodox Church and Communism: “Dukhovnoe Nasledie”: Aleksandr Shargunov: Newspaper Clippings, 1996, April-June, undated (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Saint Petersburg Russian Christian Institute for the Humanities: Vladimir Fedorov: Brochures and manuscripts, 1994, undated (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Krakhmalnikova, Zoya: Published articles, 1991-1999 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Krakhmalnikova, Zoya: Manuscripts sent to Keston, 1992 July-October (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Krakhmalnikova, Zoya: Autographed publications, 1993-1994 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Krakhmalnikova, Zoya: Presentation of the book Russian Idea and Jews: Talk by Xenia Dennen, 1994 December (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Krakhmalnikova, Zoya: Obituaries, 2008 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Krakhmalnikova, Zoya: Manuscripts, undated (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Paganism in Russia: Newspaper clippings, 1992-1999 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Paganism in Russia: Manuscript The Revival of National Paganism in Russia: Sergey Filatov, undated (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - “Ekumena” and Sandr Riga: Articles, 1991-1993 (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - “Ekumena” and Sandr Riga: “Ekumena” society lecture posters, 1992 (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - “Ekumena” and Sandr Riga: Correspondence regarding needs of Christian Ecumenists’ theatre group, 1992 (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - “Ekumena” and Sandr Riga: Interview by Xenia Dennen in Frontier, 1993 January-March (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - “Ekumena” and Sandr Riga: Samizdat publication Prizyv, 1971-1992 (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - “Ekumena” and Sandr Riga: Samizdat publication Khronika moskovskogo ekumenicheskogo soveta, 1992 January (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - Missionaries in Russia: Liberty through Jesus Mission Correspondence, 1997 — 1998 (Box 1, Folder 17)
  - Missionaries in Russia: Periodical “Osvobozhdenie v Iisuse”, 1997-1998 (Box 1, Folder 18)
  - Missionaries in Russia: Correspondence regarding Vanino Baptists Church in Russia and Rev. Dan Pollard, 1999 January (Box 1, Folder 19)
  - Missionaries in Russia: Association for Spiritual Revival “Project-250” materials, undated (Box 1, Folder 20)
  - Missionaries in Russia: Journal articles, 1994-1996 (Box 1, Folder 21)
  - Russian Orthodox Church Abroad: Newspaper articles about the Russian Orthodox Catacomb Church and opposition to the Moscow Patriarchate within the Russian Orthodox Church, 1990-1993 (Box 1, Folder 22)
  - Russian Orthodox Church Abroad: German Diocese of ROCA periodical Vestnik, 1992 (Box 1, Folder 23)
  - Russian Orthodox Church Abroad: Manuscript Persecuted Moscow Parrish Appeals to Australia: Xenia Dennen, 1993 (Box 1, Folder 24)
  - Russian Orthodox Church Abroad: Manuscript Ocherednoe razoblachenie karlovchan: Dmitry Pospielovsky, 1993 (Box 1, Folder 25)
  - Russian Orthodox Church Abroad: Information bulletin Suzdal’skii Palomnik, 1996 March (Box 1, Folder 26)
  - Russian Orthodox Church Abroad: Conflict in St. George Orthodox Church in Vodkinsk, Novoaltaisk, 1996 October-November (Box 1, Folder 27)
  - Russian Orthodox Church Abroad: Electronic articles on “unia” between the Russian Orthodox Church of MP and ROCA, 2004-2005 (Box 1, Folder 28)
  - Russian Orthodox Church Abroad: Manuscript The Russian Orthodox Church Abroad and the Catacomb Church; Changing Perspectives: Mother Evfrosinia (Molchanov), undated (Box 1, Folder 29)
  - Russian Orthodox Church Abroad: Manuscript Kolokola Oboiani: Aleksandr Nezhnyi, undated (Box 1, Folder 30)
  - Russian Orthodox Church Abroad: Manuscript Unofficial Orthodox Churches: Catacomb, free, trueEL and ROCA, undated (Box 1, Folder 31)
  - Russian Orthodox Church Abroad: Untitled manuscript, undated (Box 1, Folder 32)
  - St. Tikhon Institute. Attack on Fr. Georgii Kochetkov and Fr. Aleksandr Borisov, November 1994 (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - Brotherhood of the All-Merciful Savior and Founding of St. Tikhon Institute, 1992-1993 (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - Theological and Religious Education in Russia (1990s): Pirogov Non-Governmental School, 1991 (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - Theological and Religious Education in Russia (1990s): Program: Christmas Educational Conference, 1993 January (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - Theological and Religious Education in Russia (1990s): Articles on theological education in post-communist Russia: Mark Elliott, Wheaton College, 1994-1995 (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - Theological and Religious Education in Russia (1990s): Russian articles on Orthodox religious education and spirituality, 1997-1998 (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - Theological and Religious Education in Russia (1990s): Religious Philosophical Society for Open Christianity, 1999 (Box 2, Folder 7)
  - Theological and Religious Education in Russia (1990s): Bibliography of Fr. Andrei Kuraev’s work, undated (Box 2, Folder 8)
  - Theological and Religious Education in Russia (1990s): “Vstrecha” Society. Vladimir Poresh, undated (Box 2, Folder 9)
  - Theological and Religious Education in Russia (1990s): Abstract “Christian University’s Unique Mission” from book The Idea of a Christian College: Arthur Holmes, undated (Box 2, Folder 10)
  - Islam: Periodical clippings, 1976-1986 (Box 2, Folder 11)
  - Islam: Newspaper clippings on Afghanistan, 1979-1992 (Box 2, Folder 12)
  - Islam: Handwritten notes, undated (Box 2, Folder 13)
  - British Council of Churches visit to the USSR (16—28 May 1986): Correspondence and materials from BCC Division of International Affairs received in preparation for the trip, 1983-1986, undated (Box 2, Folder 14)
  - British Council of Churches visit to the USSR (16—28 May 1986): Articles from British Press (May-June 1986), 1986 May-June (Box 2, Folder 15)
  - British Council of Churches visit to the USSR (16—28 May 1986): Recommended reading on the Soviet Union. Typescripts and bibliography, undated (Box 2, Folder 16)
  - Abuse of Psychiatry in the USSR. Working Group (London): Brochures (in English) with reports on psychiatric abuse in the USSR, 1975-1977 (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - Abuse of Psychiatry in the USSR. Working Group (London): Working Group Minutes, 1975-1977 (Box 3, Folder 2)
  - Abuse of Psychiatry in the USSR. Working Group (London): Newspaper clippings, 1971-1976 (Box 3, Folder 3)
  - Abuse of Psychiatry in the USSR. Working Group (London): Newspaper clippings, 1977-1990 (Box 3, Folder 4)
  - Abuse of Psychiatry in the USSR. Working Group (London): General, 1972-1975 (Box 3, Folder 5)
  - Abuse of Psychiatry in the USSR. Working Group (London): General, 1976-1977 (Box 3, Folder 6)
  - Bogorodichnyi Tsentr: An autographed copy of book Bogorodichnyi tsentr: Yakov Krotov, 1992 October 6 (Box 3, Folder 7)
  - Bogorodichnyi Tsentr: Periodical Rytsar’ very, 1992 September (Box 3, Folder 8)
  - Bogorodichnyi Tsentr: Periodical Rytsar’ very, 1993 (Box 3, Folder 9)
  - Bogorodichnyi Tsentr: Periodical Frontier, 1993 April-June (Box 3, Folder 10)
  - Bogorodichnyi Tsentr: Manuscript The Center of the Mother of God: Xenia Dennen, 1993 March (Box 3, Folder 11)
  - Bogorodichnyi Tsentr: Eleven black and white 8x10 photographs (no linguistic content), undated (Box 3, Folder 12)
  - Totalitarian Sects in Russia: Materials of the International Christian Seminar “Totalitarian Cults in Russia”, 1994 (Box 3, Folder 13)
  - Totalitarian Sects in Russia: Brochures and newspaper articles, 1994-1995, undated (Box 3, Folder 14)
  - Totalitarian Sects in Russia: Brochure Chto takoe saientologiia?, undated (Box 3, Folder 15)
  - Lutherans. Church of Ingria (1 of 3), 1994-1998, undated (Box 6, Folder 1)
  - Lutherans. Church of Ingria (2 of 3), 1994-1998, undated (Box 6, Folder 2)
  - Lutherans. Church of Ingria (3 of 3), 1994-1998, undated (Box 6, Folder 3)
  - Controversy between Yakov Krotov and Keston (1998). (Box 6, Folder 4)
  - Basics of Orthodox Culture, 2003-2006 (Box 6, Folder 5)
  - Russian Law on Religion (1990s) (1 of 29), 1993-1998, undated (Box 7, Folder 1)
  - Russian Law on Religion (1990s) (2 of 29), 1993-1998, undated (Box 7, Folder 2)
  - Russian Law on Religion (1990s) (3 of 29), 1993-1998, undated (Box 7, Folder 3)
  - Russian Law on Religion (1990s) (4 of 29), 1993-1998, undated (Box 7, Folder 4)
  - Russian Law on Religion (1990s) (5 of 29), 1993-1998, undated (Box 7, Folder 5)
  - Russian Law on Religion (1990s) (6 of 29), 1993-1998, undated (Box 7, Folder 6)
  - Russian Law on Religion (1990s) (7 of 29), 1993-1998, undated (Box 7, Folder 7)
  - Russian Law on Religion (1990s) (8 of 29), 1993-1998, undated (Box 7, Folder 8)
  - Russian Law on Religion (1990s) (9 of 29), 1993-1998, undated (Box 7, Folder 9)
  - Russian Law on Religion (1990s) (10 of 29), 1993-1998, undated (Box 7, Folder 10)
  - Russian Law on Religion (1990s) (11 of 29), 1993-1998, undated (Box 7, Folder 11)
  - Russian Law on Religion (1990s) (12 of 29), 1993-1998, undated (Box 7, Folder 12)
  - Russian Law on Religion (1990s) (13 of 29), 1993-1998, undated (Box 7, Folder 13)
  - Russian Law on Religion (1990s) (14 of 29), 1993-1998, undated (Box 7, Folder 14)
  - Russian Law on Religion (1990s) (15 of 29), 1993-1998, undated (Box 7, Folder 15)
  - Russian Law on Religion (1990s) (16 of 29), 1993-1998, undated (Box 7, Folder 16)
  - Russian Law on Religion (1990s) (17 of 29), 1993-1998, undated (Box 7, Folder 17)
  - Russian Law on Religion (1990s) (18 of 29), 1993-1998, undated (Box 7, Folder 18)
  - Russian Law on Religion (1990s) (19 of 29), 1993-1998, undated (Box 7, Folder 19)
  - Russian Law on Religion (1990s) (20 of 29), 1993-1998, undated (Box 7, Folder 20)
  - Russian Law on Religion (1990s) (21 of 29), 1993-1998, undated (Box 7, Folder 21)
  - Russian Law on Religion (1990s) (22 of 29), 1993-1998, undated (Box 7, Folder 22)
  - Russian Law on Religion (1990s) (23 of 29), 1993-1998, undated (Box 7, Folder 23)
  - Russian Law on Religion (1990s) (24 of 29), 1993-1998, undated (Box 7, Folder 24)
  - Russian Law on Religion (1990s) (25 of 29), undated (Box 7, Folder 25)
  - Russian Law on Religion (1990s) (26 of 29), 1993-1998, undated (Box 7, Folder 26)
  - Russian Law on Religion (1990s) (27 of 29), 1993-1998, undated (Box 7, Folder 27)
  - Russian Law on Religion (1990s) (28 of 29), 1993-1998, undated (Box 7, Folder 28)
  - Russian Law on Religion (1990s) (29 of 29), 1993-1998, undated (Box 7, Folder 29)
  - Keston Joint Conference with SSEES: Conference program “Christianity in the Eastern Slav Lands” (16th—20th centuries), 11-15 July 1988 (Box 8, Folder 1)
  - Keston Joint Conference with SSEES 1988: Typescripts (1 of 11) (Box 8, Folder 2)
  - Keston Joint Conference with SSEES 1988: Typescripts (2 of 11) (Box 8, Folder 3)
  - Keston Joint Conference with SSEES 1988: Typescripts (3 of 11) (Box 8, Folder 4)
  - Keston Joint Conference with SSEES 1988: Typescripts (4 of 11) (Box 8, Folder 5)
  - Keston Joint Conference with SSEES 1988: Typescripts (5 of 11) (Box 8, Folder 6)
  - Keston Joint Conference with SSEES 1988: Typescripts (6 of 11) (Box 8, Folder 7)
  - Keston Joint Conference with SSEES 1988: Typescripts (7 of 11) (Box 8, Folder 8)
  - Keston Joint Conference with SSEES 1988: Typescripts (8 of 11) (Box 8, Folder 9)
  - Keston Joint Conference with SSEES 1988: Typescripts (9 of 11) (Box 8, Folder 10)
  - Keston Joint Conference with SSEES 1988: Typescripts (10 of 11) (Box 8, Folder 11)
  - Keston Joint Conference with SSEES 1988: Typescripts (11 of 11) (Box 8, Folder 12)
  - Keston Joint Conference with SSEES 1988: Information on Jews converted to Orthodox Christianity in St. Vladimir Brotherhood in 1879-1882 (in Russian), undated (Box 8, Folder 13)
  - Czechoslovakia 1968: English language newspaper clippings, 1968-1977 (Box 9, Folder 1)
  - Czechoslovakia 1968: English language newspaper clippings, 1978-1987 (Box 9, Folder 2)
  - Czechoslovakia 1968: English language newspaper clippings, 1988-2011 (Box 9, Folder 3)
  - Czechoslovakia 1968: English language newspaper clippings, undated (Box 9, Folder 4)
  - Czechoslovakia 1968: Handwritten notes, 1967-1969 (Box 9, Folder 5)
  - Czechoslovakia 1968: Handwritten notes, 1969 (Box 9, Folder 6)
  - Czechoslovakia 1968: Postcard: View of Prague Castle and Charles Bridge, undated (Box 9, Folder 7)
  - Czechoslovakia 1968 Manuscript Principal Developments in world communist affairs, 1968 June 20—July 18 (Box 9, Folder 8)
  - Czechoslovakia 1968: Reports on international and Soviet reactions, 1968 August (Box 9, Folder 9)
  - Czechoslovakia 1968: Manuscript Chronology of the Czechoslovak events, 1968 August (Box 9, Folder 10)
  - Czechoslovakia 1968: Communist comments on Czechoslovakia events, 1968 August 23-26 (Box 9, Folder 11)
  - Czechoslovakia 1968: Charter 77. Document, 1977 April 25 (Box 9, Folder 12)
  - Czechoslovakia 1968: Letter from Michael Bourdeaux to Paul Oestreicher, British Council of Churches, 1984 July 9 (Box 9, Folder 13)
  - Religion in Russia: Article: Christians and Marxists: From Dialogue to ‘Historical Compromise’?: Charles Andras, 1974 May 9 (Box 9, Folder 14)
  - Religion in Russia: Manuscript Swedenborg and Russian Mistical Tradition: Mikhail Roshchin, 1994 (Box 9, Folder 15)
  - Religion in Russia: Periodical Christianity in Russia, 1994 (Box 9, Folder 16)
  - Religion in Russia: Periodical Christianity in Russia, 1995 (Box 9, Folder 17)
  - Religion in Russia: Methodists: Newspaper clippings, 1995-1999 (Box 9, Folder 18)
  - Religion in Russia: Statistics, 1993-1996 (Box 9, Folder 19)
  - Religion in Russia: Manuscript Religiousness in Russia after the Collapse of Communism: Kimmo Kaariainen, 1996 (Folder 130)
  - Religion in Russia: Seventh-Day Adventists: Newspaper clippings, 1997-1999 (Box 9, Folder 21)
  - Religion in Russia: Newspaper clippings, 1989-1999 (Box 9, Folder 22)
  - Religion in Russia: General, 1993-1997 (Box 9, Folder 23)
  - Buddhism in Russia: Periodical in Russian and English Narthang Bulletin, 1993 (Box 10, Folder 1)
  - Buddhism in Russia: Periodical in Russian and English Narthang Bulletin, 1994 (Box 10, Folder 2)
  - Buddhism in Russia: Periodical in Russian Makhasangkha, 1994 (Box 10, Folder 3)
  - Buddhism in Russia: Periodical in Russian and English Buddhism of Russia, 1995 Autumn (Box 10, Folder 4)
  - Buddhism in Russia: Periodical in Russian and English Buddhism of Russia, 1996 Spring (Box 10, Folder 5)
  - Buddhism in Russia: Brochure in Russian Transforming Problems into Happiness: Lama Zopa Rinpoche, 1995 (Box 10, Folder 6)
  - Buddhism in Russia: Brochure in Russian Dandaron’s Case, 1974 (Box 10, Folder 7)
  - Christian Democracy, 1993-1994 (Box 10, Folder 8)
  - Starovoitova, Galina, 1998 November-December (Box 10, Folder 9)
  - Yakunin, Fr. Gleb: Brochure Muchenniki i n’iu-muchenniki, 1998 (Box 10, Folder 10)
  - Yakunin, Fr. Gleb, 1993 October-1994 October (Box 10, Folder 11)
  - Yakunin, Fr. Gleb, 1994 October-2009 May (Box 10, Folder 12)
- Collected Materials, 1931-2000, undated; 2
  The series contains materials collected by Dennen for personal research, including copies of Russian books, original publications and periodicals. The series also includes two manuscripts in English.
  - Book Chto takoe “Dukhovnoe nasledie” i pochemu ono podderzhivaet na prezidentskikh vyborakh G.A. Ziuganova: “Dukhovnoe nasledie”, 1996 (Box 2, Folder 17)
  - Book Antikhrist v Moskve: materialy obshchestvennogo komiteta "Za nravstvennoe vozrozhdenie Otechestva," v. 1, 1995 (Box 2, Folder 18)
  - Book Antikhrist v Moskve: materialy obshchestvennogo komiteta "Za nravstvennoe vozrozhdenie Otechestva," v. 2, 1996 (Box 2, Folder 19)
  - Periodical Gorizont. Publitsisticheskii i literaturno-khudozhestvennyi zhurnal, no. 8, 1991 (Box 2, Folder 20)
  - Book Moskovskii Apokalipsis: Materialy Parlamentskikh Slushanii: T.A. Astrakhankina, ed., 1996 (Box 2, Folder 21)
  - Publication of Bogorodichnyi Tsentr, Moscow: Golgofskie tainstva: Arkhiepiskop Ioann Bereslavskii, 1992 (Box 3, Folder 16)
  - Publication of Bogorodichnyi Tsentr, Moscow: Kniga Stranstvii: otkrovenie Bozhiei Materi v Rossii proroku arkhiepiskopu Ioannu (1984-1992) (Box 3, Folder 17)
  - Publication of Bogorodichnyi Tsentr, Moscow: Collected works Bogorodihnyj sobor, v.3, 1992 (Box 3, Folder 18)
  - Publication of Bogorodichnyi Tsentr, Moscow: Otkrovenie Bozhiei Materi v Rossii (1984 — 1992): Ot Skorbei k Svetu. Kniga 11. (Box 3, Folder 19)
  - Publication of Bogorodichnyi Tsentr, Moscow: Nekanonizirovannye sviatye istinnogo pravoslaviia: Innokentii Baltiiskii (1875 — 1917): Episkop Ioann (Bereslavskii), 1992 (Box 3, Folder 20)
  - Book Bogorodichnyi Tsentr: Yakov Krotov, 1992 (Box 3, Folder 21)
  - Book Episkopy i Eparkhii Russkoi Pravoslavnoi Tserkvi po sostoianiiu na 1 oktiabria 1997 goda: N. Mitrokhin and S. Timofeeva (Box 4, Folder 4)
  - Book Ekonomicheskaia deiatel’nost’ Russkoi Pravoslavnoi Tserkvi I ee tenevaia sostavliaiushchaia: ed. L. Timofeev, 2000 (Box 4, Folder 5)
  - Book Belaia Kniga: o narusheniiakh svobody sovesti v Rossiiskoi Federatsii (1994 — 1996): Obshchestvennyi komitet zashchity svobody sovesti, 1997 (Box 4, Folder 6)
  - Book Starye tserkvi, novie veruiushchie: eds. Kimmo Kaarianinen, Dmitrii Furman, 2000 (Box 4, Folder 7)
  - Brochure The Templeton Prize 1984 (Box 5, Folder 1)
  - Keston Newspaper New Witness (The Right to Believe), 1975 November (Box 5, Folder 2)
  - Keston Newspaper Religion and Communism (The Right to Believe), 1976 October (Box 5, Folder 3)
  - Keston Newspaper The Right to Believe, 1976-1987 (Box 5, Folder 4)
  - Brochure Minskaia Eparkhiia: 1793 — 2003: (Box 5, Folder 6)
  - Brochure The Russian Priests of Tomorrow, 1931-1932 (Box 5, Folder 7)
  - Brochure The Orthodox Doctrine on the Church: A. Chomiakoff, 1864 (Box 5, Folder 8)
  - Book Pushkin i ego otnoshenie k religii i Pravoslavnoj Tserkvi: Mitropolit Anastasii, 1943 (Box 5, Folder 9)
  - Book Sluzhenie mirian v tserkvi: Protoierei N. Afanas’ev, 1955 (Box 5, Folder 10)
  - Periodical Christian in Crisis, 1990 January-February (Box 5, Folder 11)
  - Periodical Christian in Crisis, 1990 June-July (Box 5, Folder 12)
  - Articles: the Russian Orthodox Church and the Russian Orthodox Church Abroad, 1996-2004 (Box 5, Folder 13)